<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Essay on Loong's Blog</title><link>https://adja.com.cn/en/tags/essay/</link><description>Recent content in Essay on Loong's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Loong</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 15:41:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adja.com.cn/en/tags/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two-month Life Experience In Hefei</title><link>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/two-month-life-experience-in-hefei/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 14:05:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/two-month-life-experience-in-hefei/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://adja.com.cn/p/two-month-life-experience-in-hefei/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Two-month Life Experience In Hefei" />&lt;h1 id="two-month-life-experience-in-hefei">Two-month Life Experience In Hefei
&lt;/h1>&lt;p> I came to Hefei at the end of July after graduation. It has been almost two months now. Let me summarize my recent life experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="work-and-rest-schedule">Work and rest schedule
&lt;/h2>&lt;p> Comparing the schedule at home and at school, I may be used to being alone, but it also makes me more focused. In addition to working 996, I spend two or three hours every day studying future work, research or professional knowledge that I am interested in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> The room is a single room rented for 750 per month, and the bathroom is shared. Considering that sometimes I go home very late at night, or the bathroom is occupied, if I need to do laundry, I must go home as early as possible (try to get home before 9:20 at the latest) or go to do laundry an hour earlier in the morning (before 7:30 in the morning) to avoid disturbing other tenants&amp;rsquo; sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> Since it only takes 20 minutes to walk to the workplace, I leave at around 8:35 every morning and arrive at my workstation 10 minutes earlier (the morning work starts at 9 o&amp;rsquo;clock).&lt;/p>
&lt;p> When it comes to working hours (although the work here refers to training, or in some schools as internship), it is relatively dull. Since I already have a solid foundation, I will choose to take time to learn more basic computer knowledge, or solve problems encountered in integrating knowledge, or make up for the lack of professional knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> The morning work starts at 9:00 and lasts until 12:00 noon. The 2 hours at noon include half an hour for lunch, half an hour for free use (for watching Bilibili or solving problems), and nearly an hour for sleep, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> The afternoon work starts at 2pm and lasts until 6 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the afternoon, followed by an hour of free time to eat dinner or do something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> I work until 9pm, and the workday is over. When I go home, I pack up my computer and go home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> I return home and turn on my computer to continue yesterday’s study tasks. Sometimes I am too tired to do anything, so I lie on the table and take a nap for an hour, or I really don’t want to study (for example, I want to watch some movies, or find some interesting novels, or my beard is too long and hard and needs to be dealt with). When I don’t want to study, I will indulge myself for a night and continue the unfinished task the next day.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="life-experience">Life experience
&lt;/h2>&lt;p> When I was studying, I usually stayed at home during holidays because my home was in the countryside. There were no entertainment venues, stalls, restaurants, or supermarkets around, which made it very troublesome to go out, eat, and shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> After graduation, I rented a house in Hefei. Although the cost of living increased, and it cost about 1,650 yuan a month (750 yuan for rent + 900 yuan for food), it was extremely convenient for receiving express delivery, shopping, eating, and traveling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> However, big cities also have some disadvantages (maybe not for others). There are many bridges and subways here, and various codes are required for travel, which is very unfriendly for rural people who come to big cities for the first time. In addition, the inaccurate positioning of mobile phone navigation is a headache.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> During the rental period, there was a bad thing of toilet blockage. It was probably because the tenants were used to throwing toilet paper directly into the toilet after using it. Although the problem was solved in about a week, it was really uncomfortable to use the bathroom during this period.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="work-experience">Work experience
&lt;/h2>&lt;p> If you love computers, working 996 hours a day is actually nothing. You can still improve a lot in the process and learn a lot of useful things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> In the past two months of work and study, I always felt that something was missing. Later, I gradually found that I was missing the passion I had when I first entered university. Although I get along well with the people around me and often help others solve their doubts, there is always a sense of distance between us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> Despite this, I still hope that I can maintain myself and keep improving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future-plans">Future plans
&lt;/h2>&lt;p> Considering that I plan to work on drivers or low-level development in the future, I will study kernels and assembly languages under other architectures in my spare time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> The two months of living in Hefei, although generally much better than at home, still do not meet my expectations. Maybe it is because my current life does not meet my expectations, or I cannot meet people who are good enough or like-minded. I will definitely take the postgraduate entrance examination in the next two to three years. However, before that, I need to lay a solid foundation (mainly operating systems and computer composition principles) and find the direction I want to study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> In addition, since Hefei has a complete range of industries and is developing high-tech technologies (nuclear fusion, quantum chips), the future is bright, both now and in the future. If I work in the future, I will most likely work in Hefei, which can be regarded as a contribution to my hometown.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>2023-09-23 Updated&lt;/font>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>