<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Journal on Loong's Blog</title><link>https://adja.com.cn/en/tags/journal/</link><description>Recent content in Journal on Loong's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Loong</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:25:31 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adja.com.cn/en/tags/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>National Day Records in 2025</title><link>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/national-day-records-in-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:39:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/national-day-records-in-2025/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://adja.com.cn/p/national-day-records-in-2025/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post National Day Records in 2025" />&lt;h1 id="national-day-records-in-2025">National Day Records in 2025
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>Today is the last day of the National Day holiday, and work will resume tomorrow. Taking advantage of the last day of the holiday, I am recording my life during this National Day holiday and summarizing my recent life status.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="life-during-the-national-day-holiday">Life During the National Day Holiday
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>During this National Day holiday, I mostly stayed at home. My parents arrived in Hefei on the first evening. The annoying part was that in the following days, my parents kept trying to set me up with online dating matches. On the fifth day, both sets of parents and the children had a meal together. Both sets of parents were quite satisfied, but the match was not my type, and there was no further contact afterward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the sixth day of the holiday, it was the Mid-Autumn Festival. The whole family stayed at home and had a reunion dinner. On the seventh day, my parents returned to their hometown. I played games with my classmates, and on the eighth day, I stayed alone in my room to summarize this holiday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, this National Day holiday was quite uneventful. The issue of my parents urging me to get married has temporarily come to an end, and they will not interfere too much in my life anymore. I can return to my three-point-one-line lifestyle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="summary-of-recent-life-status">Summary of Recent Life Status
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Since July, work has become busy, and I have gradually taken on some of the leader&amp;rsquo;s tasks. Every week, I summarize the issues from the previous week or share some development experiences and team collaboration norms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to the increased time spent on work, I need to take time to summarize all members&amp;rsquo; issues. However, I often encounter situations where members do not participate. Therefore, in the absence of anything to report, I can only take time to organize development documents or learn some new technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside of work, I have started long-distance running and have persisted for more than two months, accumulating nearly 100 kilometers of running. I aim to complete the 100-kilometer achievement this week and will continue to persist in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>Updated on 2025-10-08&lt;/font>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long Term Planning</title><link>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/long-term-planning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 09:34:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/long-term-planning/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://adja.com.cn/p/long-term-planning/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Long Term Planning" />&lt;h1 id="long-term-planning">Long Term Planning
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>In the past, I was always anxious, thinking too much, and struggling too much, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve enough outstanding results. Now I think that this
anxiety may be caused by not having a clear goal and plan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next period of time, I will try to use some efficiency tools and make long-term plans. In addition, I will pay attention to exercise, maintain
a fresh appearance, go out more often to meet like-minded people, and hope to find a partner who can promote each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, I will update this plan regularly to see if I am moving towards my goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align: left">Time&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align: left">Planning&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Completion&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2024.11~2025.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Rust basics&lt;/td>
&lt;td>√&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2025.3~2025.4&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Dart basics&lt;/td>
&lt;td>√&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;s>2025.4~2025.8&lt;/s>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;s>Learn flutter&lt;/s>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;s>10%&lt;/s>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;s>2025.4~2025.11&lt;/s>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;s>Learn godot&lt;/s>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;s>0% &lt;/s>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2025.6~2025.11&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">egui&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30%&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">2025.6~2025.12&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left">Find friends of the opposite sex&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0%&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>Updated on 2025-04-20&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Now it is May 6, 2025, the Labor Day holiday has just ended, and the server I bought during college has expired. I have been exploring Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s
Pages and Workers, and to reduce hassle, I will host the website on Cloudflare in the future, while continuing to use the original domain name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, I was using Hugo version 0.128.2 to build the website, and the latest version has been updated to 0.147.1. The theme has also changed a
lot, so I took the opportunity of this holiday to update everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regarding the plan to learn Flutter and Godot, I compared other rendering engines and felt that technology is developing too fast. I still need to
delve into the underlying layers, so I will proceed with the original plan for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In terms of finding friends of the opposite sex, I tried online dating once, but I felt that the other party was quite passive, so I guess we can only
remain strangers. My parents also talked to other parents online, but it seems that most of them didn&amp;rsquo;t work out, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just let fate decide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My parents came to my workplace during the holiday, and our family went back to our hometown to have some fun. The town has changed a lot, with new
houses waiting to be occupied and tourist attractions under construction. I hope that my hometown will get better and better in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>Updated on 2025-05-06&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Today is May 25, and two weeks ago, the weekly holiday was changed to a double weekend, giving me more time to invest in things I am interested in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read some articles online about graphical user interface development, such as app development frameworks (Flutter, React Native, Tarui, etc.) and
game engines (Godot, Unity, Cocos, Bevy, etc.). I realized that my original idea was too naive, wanting to make both apps and games, so I hesitated
about which engine to learn and even downloaded Unity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to produce results quickly, I need to give up Godot and invest all my time in Flutter, while also casually learning about Rust-related
development in my spare time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>Updated on 2025-05-25&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>It is July 21st, and more than two months have passed. Two months ago, after comparing various GUI frameworks, I decided to temporarily give up &lt;code>flutter&lt;/code>, and have been thinking about &lt;code>egui&lt;/code> afterward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since asynchronous waiting operations are not allowed in the loop of &lt;code>egui&lt;/code>, channels must be used to transfer data. When an event occurs, the app retains the receiving channel, creates a thread in the background to process the data, and sends the data to the app through the channel after processing. Each time the app loops, it checks the receiving channel data and updates the interface after receiving the data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When trying to integrate simple asynchronous operations into &lt;code>egui&lt;/code>, it is also necessary to solve the problem of multi-threaded shared resources. Use &lt;code>Arc&amp;lt;Mutex&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code> to share data; if read and write operations are performed simultaneously in multiple threads, &lt;code>RwLock&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code> needs to be used to share data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, code reuse and structure also need to be considered. Use the &lt;code>App&lt;/code> trait of &lt;code>egui&lt;/code> to define the structure of the application, and use &lt;code>egui::Context&lt;/code> to manage status and events. Recently, I found a project for reference, hoping that it will be helpful for subsequent development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>Updated on 2025-07-21&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>It has been a month since the last update. Due to being responsible for tracking and handling issues within the team, my spare time has been significantly reduced. If I work overtime until 9 pm every night, I go for a run in the nearby park. Looking back at my check-in records, although I can&amp;rsquo;t stick to it every day, I have been exercising an average of 3 days a week since mid-July, and I will continue to maintain this habit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my spare time, I have used &lt;code>egui&lt;/code> simply and found that if I design complex functions poorly, maintaining the code can be quite laborious. Therefore, I started to pay attention to &lt;code>Bevy&lt;/code>, whose design philosophy and &lt;code>ECS&lt;/code> architecture enlightened me. Recently, I have roughly understood the basic concepts of &lt;code>Bevy&lt;/code>, and I will try to use &lt;code>Bevy&lt;/code> to create some small projects in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>Updated on 2025-08-24&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Summary of 2024</title><link>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/summary-of-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 12:38:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://adja.com.cn/en/p/summary-of-2024/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://adja.com.cn/p/summary-of-2024/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Summary of 2024" />&lt;h1 id="summary-of-2024">Summary of 2024
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>It has been more than a year since I started working. During this time, I have experienced a lot and learned a lot. This article is a summary of 2024.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="work">Work
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>My work mainly involves firmware development for microcontrollers. After a year of training, I can basically handle this job. In this year, I have learned a lot, such as teamwork, development tool usage skills, and the use of common peripherals of microcontrollers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this period, I also encountered many problems, but with the help of leaders and colleagues, they were all solved. Every time I encounter a problem, I will first think about it myself, and then think about how to improve it on the basis of mastery, such as improving the readability, reusability, and convenience of the code. In every detail, I try to do my best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my spare time, I also tried to learn some new technologies and tried to apply them to work, such as using &lt;strong>Renode&lt;/strong> to improve the efficiency of firmware development, trying gitlab&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD to compile firmware, etc. Although I have made a lot of efforts, the effect is not very good, mainly due to the lack of participation of members, too much work, too little time, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="life">Life
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Because I went to work in a different place alone after graduation, everything in life has to be taken care of by myself, which is a challenge for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because I live in a very remote place, and because of my personality and other reasons, I basically stay at home, read novels, play Warcraft, and tinker with some technology in my spare time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first half of the year, when I was not busy, I migrated my blog from hexo to hugo, which makes it more convenient to write articles and easier to maintain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, if I have time, I will play games with my classmates, which can relax and keep in touch with my classmates.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="outlook-for-2025">Outlook for 2025
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Although I found a job in 2023, which was a year of graduation and unemployment, considering that the number of graduates is still increasing in the future, the future competition will be more intense. In my spare time, I need to continue to maintain sensitivity to technology and have the opportunity to meet more people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, it is troublesome to set up a network in different places when playing games with friends. Next, I will try to refer to some open-source projects and develop a simple networking tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;font size=3 color=blue>2023-02-02 Updated&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>